Ekaterina Orlova

Full Stack Developer

Haifa | 054-643-2376 | katva.leemi@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Fullstack Web Developer experienced in React with a previous background of a Project Manager in the Game Development industry. With this expertise I know how to organize myself and others to design high-quality products and deliver them on time. Always concerned about consistent and smooth UX being a picky user myself. Not afraid of building the server-side (hello, Node.js + express!) and databases of any type.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, Node.is, git, HTML5, CSS, Tailwind, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Online Therapy Service with a real-time chat - Github | Demo

A React App for finding and chatting with a therapist built with Node is REST API, data stored in Mongo.db database.

- Created REST API with Express is routers to handle various requests including authentication
- Implemented authentication and token verification with JWT
- Stored data in the non-relational database (Mongo.db) which was connected to server via Mongoose library
- Integrated Socket.io to handle real-time messages exchange
- Styled the app with customized Material UI library and Tailwind

Trading center application - Github | Demo

A React app trading center with information of current exchange rates and a graph of Silver/Gold Ratio

- Broke down project to separate components and CSS modules to achieve high readability and manageability of code
- Fetched data from 2 different APIs and rendered it to components
- Employed Mock Service Worker (MSW) to imitate API calls during development stage to speed up the process
- Added and configured ChartJS library to create dynamic graph

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer Moscow, Russia Innova (gaming industry, high-tech) 2020 - 2022

- Implemented marketing landing pages employing internal UI-library, closely interacting with product team
- Maintained and added new features to a big React web-project with Microfrontend architecture
- Worked in Agile (sprints, weekly plannings, retrospectives, JIRA) and CI/CD

Senior Project Manager

Moscow, Russia

Innova (gaming industry, high-tech)

2015 - 2020

- Launched an online computer game and reached given profit KPIs
- Coordinated design and development of web-sites, which led to an increase in amount of users and profit
- Managed a full-cycle of the mobile app launch: from requirements to development

Marketing Manager Moscow, Russia

Social Discovery Ventures

2014 - 2015

- Developed and ran partnership programs in a way to increase conversion rates
- Analyzed marketing reports to find fraudulent traffic, which allowed to cut costs

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development, JavaScript full-time program

Developers Institute, TLV Coding Bootcamp

Tel Aviv. Israel 01/2023 - 04/2023

Master of Arts, Media and Communication Science

Technische Universität Ilmenau

Ilmenau, Germany 09/2015 - 07/2017

Bachelor, Management in Advertising and PR

National Research University Higher School of Economics

Moscow, Russia 09/2010 - 07/2014

LANGUAGES

Russian - native speaker, English - proficient, Hebrew - limited working